Gajula Shaik Mohammad Furqan

MERN | Full Stack Developer

Email: gsmfurqan@gmail.com | Contact: 8639410779 | Address: Andhra Pradesh

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gsm-furgan-199912ju/ | Portfolio: furgan-portfolio.vercel.app/

GitHub: GSMFURQAN

PROFILE

React.Js Developer with 4 years of Experience in Web Development. Proficient in developing new user-facing features, determining the structure and design of web pages, building reusable codes, optimizing page loading times, and using a variety of markup languages to create the application. Good focus, communication, and collaboration skills. Ability to learn fast, adapt, pay attention to detail, strong problem-solving, troubleshooting, and management skills. Self-motivated in learning new skills, technologies, and evolving trends.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript

Front-end Technologies: React.js, Redux, Tool-kit, Hooks, React Native, Next JS

Back-end Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Graphql, Firebase

Libraries: Material UI, Chakra UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Scss

Tools: JIRA, Git, GitHub, Git Lab, Bit Bucket, VS code, Swagger, Postman, Thunder

client, Apollo client, Trello

Work Environment: Agile, Scrum methodology

WORK EXPERIENCE (4 years)

Full Stack Developer at Verraxis Technologies, Pune

Dec 2022 - Present

Project 5 – Solicitors (Open Site) Requires VPN

- Client: Govt of Canada, Nova Scotia
- Managed client relationships for the Government of Canada, Nova Scotia. Developed a Client
 Management system, utilizing React, to store and track client data, files, and activities, and
 schedule meetings, with automated court notifications via email. Designed a calendar and
 event planner dashboard integrated with O365 contacts, leveraging React Big Calendars, and
 created a timeline for activities
- Optimized application performance by 25% using React Query by controlling API calls and caching and reduced server load.

Project 4 – Procurement (Open Site) Requires VPN

- Client: Govt of Canada, Nova Scotia
- Collaborated with a highly skilled development team to create a platform and handled 80% of REST API Integrations to post, view, manage, and award tenders to the bidders. Created an admin dashboard, advanced filter page, file upload system, and tables for the application. Built high-quality, reusable components using Material UI, and utility functions for cross-application reuse and developed applications 2 times faster.

Project 3 – **FutureWell** (https://authen.com/)

- Client: Authen
- Authen enables consumers and supply chain participants to ensure authenticity, traceability, and sustainability. It provides a total view of data—tracking the entire supply chain journey and helps to calculate the carbon footprint of each stage.

• Worked on Authen's FutureWell project on both the front and back end, developing authentication and a role-based login system with JWT, profile page, and dashboard, and created a series of dynamic forms using the yup library.

React Js Developer at Shethink, Indore

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

Project 2 – SourceBae (https://sourcebae.com/)

- Client: SourceBae
- Developed a Responsive Web application for SourceBae, an employee outsourcing platform, for client Shethink, where clients and agencies can select developers with required skills and choose packages based on project needs. Translated Figma wireframes into high-quality code, created a User Interface and implemented animations and transitions using Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS.
- Conducted thorough performance testing and debugging to ensure the application functioned as expected, resolving issues during development

Software Developer at Infosys, Hyderabad

Jan 2021 – Aug 2022

Project 1- Verizon

- Client: Verizon
- Spearheaded API integration and debugged the ticket-tracking application, ensuring seamless consumer issue resolution across multiple teams for Verizon.

GOAL: To become an Application Architect

EDUCATION

- **2016 2020 B. TECH EEE** 8.6 CGPA, Hindustan University, Chennai.
- **2014 2016 Intermediate** MPC 95.4%, Sri Chaitanya College, Vijayawada.
- **2014 SSC** 9.7 GPA Keshava Reddy School, Andhra Pradesh

PERSONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: English, Telugu, Hindi, Urdu

• Location: Kurnool, Andhra Pradesh